Austin Chi

Anaheim, California, United States



linkedin.com/in/austin-chi-a9b418115



austinchi2@yahoo.com

Summary

Received Masters of Science in Statistics at University of California, Riverside. Received Bachelor of Arts and Science (B.A.S.) double majored in Statistics and Economics from University of California, Davis.

Working in data science, the development and application of neural networks and other machine learning methods, in various problem domains including, computer vision, Natural Language Processing, marketing, and ecology.

4 years of using R for statistical analysis and predictive modeling in various problem domains.

4 years of experience in Python using libraries such as Pytorch and Tensorflow with deep learning models.

1 year in quantitative and behavior marketing research.

Experience



Machine Learning Engineer

AWM Smart Shelf

Sep 2019 - Present (8 months +)

Worked on real-time product image recognition for frictionless stores, including efficient distributed inference pipeline, and dynamic creation of scene specific image transformation.

Worked on backend cart logic for frictionless store

Created the backend for store wide dynamic planogram capable of real time tracking of placed and misplaced objects.

Created prototype for produce recognizer and counter.

Technical Editor

Journal of Electronic Commerce Research

Aug 2015 - Present (4 years 9 months +)

JECR is a top ranked e-commerce academic journal. I help the Chief Editor proofread statistical models for validity for manuscripts submitted to the journal.

• Data Scientist

Rule14 LLC

Jul 2019 - Feb 2020 (8 months)

Worked on a large scale high throughput computer vision project integrating tabular data into CNN models to make intelligent decisions based on image and metadata, as well as other analytics consulting work using tabular data.



Trilogy Education

Aug 2018 - Aug 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Trilogy Education, specializes in coding boot camps nationwide in schools such as UCLA, UC Berkeley, and UT Austin.

One-on-One Online tutoring for Data Visualization Boot camp that covers python, sql, nosql, javascript, and html in a data science and visualization context. Received all positive comments from students.

UCR Teaching Assistant

University of California, Riverside

Oct 2018 - Jul 2019 (10 months)

Taught Econometrics ECN 107 in Fall 2018 for three sections of total 90 students. Independently conducted labs and discussions.

Received an overall student evaluation of 93.75 percentile as an effective teacher among all teaching assistants in the department.

Taught Introduction to Microeconomics ECN 003 for three sections of total 90 students. Independently conducted class discussions.

Received an overall student evaluation of 86.36 percentile as an effective teacher among all teaching assistants in the department.

Teaching Introduction to Macroeconomics ECN 002 for three sections of total 90 students. Independently conducted class discussions.

Data Analyst

Virscend University

Aug 2017 - Jul 2019 (2 years)

Helped the Deputy Director of Admission to analyzed data from google analytics to pinpoint potential demographics for student recruitment.

Gave a guest lecturer in Big Data and its Application for an MBA class.

Conducted two training sections of Google Analytics.

gamania Big Data and Machine Learning Intern

Gamania Digital Entertainment

Aug 2018 - Aug 2018 (1 month)

Gamania Digital Entertainment, one of the largest game development studios in Taiwan. 1 month Collected data for and developed a Natural Language Processing (NLP), and video view prediction model using pytorch for reading forum posts.

Created Tableau and Power BI dashboards for use in conjunction with Google Analytics Data for analyzing the company's website and server usages.

Education

UCR University of California, Riverside

Master's degree, Statistics 2017 - 2019

University of California, Davis

Bachelor of Arts and Science (B.A.S.), Economics And Statistics 2013 - Jun 2017

Honors & Awards

Dean's List - UC Davis College of Letters and Science

Made the Deans List for Winter of 2014



Dean's List - UC Davis College of Letters and Science

Made the Dean's List for Fall of 2016

Skills

Python • Computer Vision • PyTorch • Research • Statistics • Data Analysis • Statistical Modeling • Econometrics • Deep Learning • R